Chenxi Liu

Updated: July, 2024

Email: liuchenxi0921@gmail.com
Web: https://chenxil21.github.io/

Research Interests

My Ph.D. research consists of attempts to bridge rough freehand line drawings with precise digital representations and also to robustly generate line drawings based on 3D models. My future goal is to better understand as well as assist drawing and visual creation in general.

Education

Sep 2016 – Jun 2023	University of British Columbia Ph.D. in Computer Graphics. Advised by Prof. Alla Sheffer.
Aug 2013 – Dec 2014	Carnegie Mellon University M.S. in Computer Science.
Sep 2009 – Jun 2013	Beihang University B.Eng. in Computer Science and Technology. Ranking: 2/188.

Publications

Siqi Wang, **Chenxi Liu**, Daniele Panozzo, Denis Zorin, and Alec Jacobson. Bézier spline simplification using locally integrated error metrics. *ACM Trans. Graph.*, 2023

Chenxi Liu. *Processing freehand vector sketches*. Ph.D. thesis, University of British Columbia, 2023. Eurographics 2024 PhD Thesis Award, Honorable Mention

Chenxi Liu, Toshiki Aoki, Mikhail Bessmeltsev, and Alla Sheffer. Stripmaker: Perception-driven learned vector sketch consolidation. *ACM Trans. Graph.*, 42(4), jul 2023

Chenxi Liu, Pierre Bénard, Aaron Hertzmann, and Shayan Hoshyari. Contesse: Accurate occluding contours for subdivision surfaces. *ACM Trans. Graph.*, 42(1), February 2023

Jerry Yin*, **Chenxi Liu***, Rebecca Lin, Nicholas Vining, Helge Rhodin, and Alla Sheffer. Detecting viewer-perceived intended vector sketch connectivity. *ACM Trans. Graph.*, 41, 2022. *Joint first authors

Dave Pagurek van Mossel, **Chenxi Liu**, Nicholas Vining, Mikhail Bessmeltsev, and Alla Sheffer. Strokestrip: Joint parameterization and fitting of stroke clusters. *ACM Trans. Graph.*, 40(4), 2021

Yulia Gryaditskaya, Felix Hähnlein, **Chenxi Liu**, Alla Sheffer, and Adrien Bousseau. Lifting freehand concept sketches into 3d. *ACM Trans. Graph.*, 39(6):1–16, 2020

Chenxi Liu, Enrique Rosales, and Alla Sheffer. Strokeaggregator: Consolidating raw sketches

into artist-intended curve drawings. ACM Trans. Graph., 37(4), 2018

Chenxi Liu, Jessica Hodgins, and James McCann. Whole-cloth quilting patterns from photographs. In *Proceedings of the Symposium on Non-Photorealistic Animation and Rendering*, NPAR'17, July 2017

Lea Albaugh, April Grow, **Chenxi Liu**, James McCann, Gillian Smith, and Jennifer Mankoff. Threadsteading: Playful interaction for textile fabrication devices. In *Proceedings of the 2016 CHI Conference Extended Abstracts*, pages 285–288. ACM, 2016

Research & Professional Experience

Jul 2023 – Present	DGP Lab, University of Toronto Postdoctoral Fellow. Supervised by Prof. Alec Jacobson.
Mar 2023 – Jun 2023	Adobe Research Research Intern. Supervised by Deepali Aneja and Prof. Alec Jacobson.
Sep 2016 – Feb 2023	Digital Geometry Processing Group, Imager Lab, UBC Research Assistant. Advised by Prof. Alla Sheffer. Conducting research on the artistic creation tools.
May 2020 – Nov 2020	Adobe Research Research Intern. Supervised by Aaron Hertzmann. Conducted research on non-photorealistic line drawing generation.
Mar 2015 – Jul 2016	Textile Lab, Disney Research Pittsburgh Research Associate. Supervised by Dr. James McCann & Prof. Jessica Hodgins. Conducted research on automatic quilting pattern generation using CNC quilting machine and graph theory.
Jul 2014 – Aug 2014	CMU Graphics Lab Research Assistant. Advised by Prof. Kayvon Fatahalian. Built a visualization module for a lighting control framework using Arnold.
Jul 2012 – Sep 2012	Microsoft Search Technology Center Asia Intern, Software Development Engineer in Test. Wrote scripts to gather statistical data and create analyses from search engine logs.
Aug 2011 – Dec 2011	Laboratory for Information Security and Intelligent Informa- tion Processing, Beihang University Research Assistant. Advised by Prof. Zhoujun Li. Built a tool to capture software exception messages.

Honors

Apr 2024	Eurographics 2024 PhD Thesis Award, Honorable Mention Eurographics and the Computer Graphics Forum Journal.
Feb 2024	Faculty of Arts & Science Postdoctoral Fellowship Faculty of Arts & Science, University of Toronto.
May 2022	WiGRAPH Rising Stars The ACM Community Group for Women in Computer Graphics Research.
Oct 2016	Technology Award Winner: Threadsteading IndieCade'16.
Nov 2011	National Scholarship (Top 1% in Academic Performance) Ministry of Education of the People's Republic of China.
Dec 2012, 2011, 2010	The First Prize Scholarship of Academic Performance Beihang University.

Talks & Exhibition

Jun 2024	SGP'24 Graduate School Course: Fundamentals and Applications of Sketch Processing.
Aug 2023	SIGGRAPH'23 Conference Presenter: ConTesse: Accurate Occluding Contours for Subdivision Surfaces. StripMaker: Perception-driven Learned Vector Sketch Consolidation.
Fall 2022	University of Toronto, Université de Montréal, University of Surrey Invited Talk: Cleaning Up Vector Sketches Made by Humans and Computers.
Aug 2022	SIGGRAPH'22 Conference Presenter: Detecting Viewer-Perceived Intended Vector Sketch Connectivity.
Aug 2018	SIGGRAPH'18 Conference Presenter: Strokeaggregator: Consolidating raw sketches into artist-intended curve drawings.
Jul 2017	NPAR'17 Conference Presenter: Whole-cloth quilting patterns from photographs.
Mar 2016	Alt.Ctrl.GDC, Game Developers Conference Exhibitor: Threadsteading. (Game also attended CHI Interactivity, 2016. IndieCade, 2016)

Teaching Experience

Fall, 2023 **CSC317@UofT: Computer Graphics** Guest Lecturer and Co-Developer of LEAF+ Project (Understanding the Limits of Al-Based Image Generators with DALL E 2 and Midjourney). Project Lead: Prof. Alec Jacobson. CPSC424@UBC: Geometric Modeling Winter 1, 2022 Graduate Teaching Assistant, Instructor: Prof. Alla Sheffer. Instructional Skills Workshops for Grad Students@UBC Winter, 2019 Winter 2, 2018 CPSC436D@UBC: Video Game Programming Graduate Teaching Assistant, Instructor: Prof. Alla Sheffer. Winter 2, 2016 **CPSC418@UBC: Parallel Computation** Graduate Teaching Assistant, Instructor: Prof. Mark Greenstreet.

Undergraduate Advising

2023 – Present Sepehr Ghasemipour University of Toronto.

2023 – 2024 Silvia Lopez University of Toronto.

2022 – 2023 Toshiki Aoki University of Tokyo.

Services

DGP Academy
Project Lead: Low-Poly Fabrication. Media.

Conference and Journal Paper Review
SIGGRAPH'22,23,24. SIGGRAPH Asia'22,24. Eurographics'20,22,23,24.
Pacific Graphics'20,24. TVCG'23. CGF'22,24. IEEE CG&A'20.
TPAMI'19. SCF'19. UIST'24.

Craduate Student Recruiting Committee
Student Representative of Computer Graphics.

AMORE Seminar

Skills

Programming: C/C++, Python, MATLAB, Java, SQL.

Libraries and Tools: libigl, CGAL, scikit-learn, CUDA, OpenCL, OpenGL, CMake, Git.

Imager Lab seminar organizer.

Visual Editing: Illustrator, Photoshop, Premiere.

References

Alec Jacobson (Postdoc supervisor, jacobson@cs.toronto.edu), University of Toronto. Alla Sheffer (Ph.D. supervisor, sheffa@cs.ubc.ca), University of British Columbia. Aaron Hertzmann (internship mentor, hertzman@dgp.toronto.edu), Adobe Research.